<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filament on PrintUpgraded</title>
    <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/categories/filament/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filament on PrintUpgraded</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/categories/filament/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASA vs ABS: Which Filament Is Better for Outdoor Prints?</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/asa-vs-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/asa-vs-abs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article may contain affiliate links. We may earn a small commission if you buy something through them, at no extra cost to you. We only recommend products we&amp;rsquo;d actually use ourselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;asa-vs-abs-which-filament-is-better-for-outdoor-prints&#34;&gt;ASA vs ABS: Which Filament Is Better for Outdoor Prints?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re comparing ASA vs ABS filament for outdoor prints, ASA wins. It&amp;rsquo;s basically ABS with UV resistance built in. Parts printed in ASA hold up in direct sunlight for years without yellowing, cracking, or getting brittle. ABS degrades in UV light within months. For anything that lives outside, ASA is the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best PLA Filament Brands: Top Picks for Reliable Prints</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/best-pla-filament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/best-pla-filament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; Some links in this article are affiliate links. We earn a small commission if you buy through them. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost you extra and doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect our recommendations. See our &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/affiliate-disclosure/&#34;&gt;affiliate disclosure&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;best-pla-filament-brands-top-picks-for-reliable-prints&#34;&gt;Best PLA Filament Brands: Top Picks for Reliable Prints&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best PLA filament brands give you consistent diameter, accurate colors, and clean prints without constant troubleshooting. After testing dozens of spools across multiple printers, these five brands deliver the most reliable results. If you just want one answer, Overture PLA is our top pick for the best balance of quality and price.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filament Drying Guide: Why It Matters and How to Do It Right</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/filament-drying-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/filament-drying-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;filament-drying-guide-why-it-matters-and-how-to-do-it-right&#34;&gt;Filament Drying Guide: Why It Matters and How to Do It Right&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wet filament is one of the most common causes of bad 3D prints. If your prints have rough surfaces, popping sounds, stringing, or weak layers, moisture is probably the problem. Filament drying is simple. You just need to apply gentle heat for a few hours. This guide covers why it matters, how to spot the signs, and the best ways to dry and store your filament.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Print PETG: Settings, Tips, and Common Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-petg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-petg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-print-petg-settings-tips-and-common-mistakes&#34;&gt;How to Print PETG: Settings, Tips, and Common Mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PETG is one of the best filaments for functional prints. But if you try printing it with your PLA settings, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a stringy mess. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to print PETG properly, with the right temperatures, retraction settings, and tips to avoid the most common mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still deciding whether PETG is right for your project, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/pla-vs-petg-vs-abs/&#34;&gt;PLA vs PETG vs ABS comparison&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Print TPU Flexible Filament: A Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-tpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-tpu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-print-tpu-flexible-filament-a-beginners-guide&#34;&gt;How to Print TPU Flexible Filament: A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Printing TPU is easier than most people think. You just need the right settings and a little patience. If you know how to print TPU properly, you can make phone cases, drone bumpers, gaskets, shoe insoles, and anything else that needs to bend without breaking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TPU (thermoplastic polyurethane) is a flexible, rubber-like filament. It&amp;rsquo;s completely different from rigid materials like PLA, PETG, or ABS. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how TPU compares to those options, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/pla-vs-petg-vs-abs/&#34;&gt;filament comparison guide&lt;/a&gt; for the full breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nylon Filament Printing Guide: Settings and Tips</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-nylon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-nylon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article may contain affiliate links. We may earn a small commission if you buy something through them, at no extra cost to you. We only recommend products we&amp;rsquo;d actually use ourselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;nylon-filament-printing-guide-settings-and-tips&#34;&gt;Nylon Filament Printing Guide: Settings and Tips&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nylon filament printing gives you parts that are tough, wear-resistant, and slightly flexible. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the strongest materials you can print at home. But it&amp;rsquo;s also one of the hardest to get right. Nylon absorbs moisture from the air like a sponge, needs high temperatures, and warps aggressively. If you know what to expect and set things up correctly, the results are worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLA vs PETG vs ABS: Complete Filament Comparison Guide</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/pla-vs-petg-vs-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/pla-vs-petg-vs-abs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pla-vs-petg-vs-abs-complete-filament-comparison-guide&#34;&gt;PLA vs PETG vs ABS: Complete Filament Comparison Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re comparing PLA vs PETG vs ABS, here&amp;rsquo;s the short answer. PLA is the easiest to print and best for beginners. PETG is stronger and more heat-resistant. ABS is the toughest but hardest to work with. The right choice depends on what you&amp;rsquo;re printing and where it&amp;rsquo;ll be used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break down exactly how these three filaments compare so you can pick the right one for your project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
