<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beginner-Guide on PrintUpgraded</title>
    <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/tags/beginner-guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beginner-Guide on PrintUpgraded</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/tags/beginner-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Print TPU Flexible Filament: A Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-tpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/how-to-print-tpu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-print-tpu-flexible-filament-a-beginners-guide&#34;&gt;How to Print TPU Flexible Filament: A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Printing TPU is easier than most people think. You just need the right settings and a little patience. If you know how to print TPU properly, you can make phone cases, drone bumpers, gaskets, shoe insoles, and anything else that needs to bend without breaking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TPU (thermoplastic polyurethane) is a flexible, rubber-like filament. It&amp;rsquo;s completely different from rigid materials like PLA, PETG, or ABS. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how TPU compares to those options, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/pla-vs-petg-vs-abs/&#34;&gt;filament comparison guide&lt;/a&gt; for the full breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OrcaSlicer Beginner Guide: Setup and First Print</title>
      <link>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/orcaslicer-beginner-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/blog/orcaslicer-beginner-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post may contain affiliate links. If you buy through these links, we may earn a small commission at no extra cost to you. &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc18267.github.io/printupgraded/disclosure/&#34;&gt;Full disclosure here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;orcaslicer-beginner-guide-setup-and-first-print&#34;&gt;OrcaSlicer Beginner Guide: Setup and First Print&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OrcaSlicer is a free, open-source slicer that started as a fork of BambuStudio (which itself forked from PrusaSlicer). It&amp;rsquo;s become one of the most popular slicers in the 3D printing community thanks to its built-in calibration tools, fast slicing, and excellent multi-color support. This OrcaSlicer beginner guide will walk you through downloading, setting up, and making your first print.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
